# Callum Wright

07511467130 / wrightci01s@gmail.com github.com/KAHLYM

Software Engineer with over 3 years of professional experience developing industry leading cybersecurity software using C/C++ and Python. Enthused by consistent and well structured design. Web development technologies are of interest as they offer opportunities that are more design orientated.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

**Sophos**, *Abingdon*, Jun 2017 - Present *Software Engineer III* Continued development on HitmanPro.Alert.

Jul 2021 - Present

Software Engineer II

Aug 2019 - Jul 2021

Developed HitmanPro.Alert; a behavioural based exploit mitigation product (C/C++ and Python).

- Refactored tracking of system processes and associated metadata
- Reduced time to analyse detection occurrence from ~10 hours per month to a single query by integrating batched analytics made available through Kibana; a data visualisation dashboard

Software Engineer Intern (University Placement)

Jun 2017 - Aug 2018

Developed Windows Server products Update Cache and Message Relay (C/C++ and Python).

- Implemented certification chain validation to prevent impersonation attacks

### **EDUCATION**

## Loughborough University, Loughborough

Computer Science BSc Second Class Honors, Upper Division

Sep 2015 - Jul 2019

Final Year Project: Classification of Environmental Sound Events

Final Year Modules: Advanced Artificial Intelligence Systems; Agent Based Systems; Algorithm Analysis; Cloud Computing; Computer Vision; Cryptography and Network Security; Data Mining; Robotics

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Worked solely on all projects and managed all aspects from conception to release.

## **Financial Market Sentiment Analysis**

Mar 2021, Nov 2021 - Present

Early stages of development with the intention to create a UI that highlights financial market movement using sentiment analysis (Angular, Firebase and Python).

#### **Personal Website**

Jun 2020 - Jul 2020 (refactored throughout 2021)

A portfolio that acts as a single gateway to provide an overview of myself professionally and personally and is available at callumwright.com (Firebase and React).

Whanalysis Dec 2019 - May 2020

Whanalysis is a web application that analyses WhatsApp conversation and provides shareable analysis through an accessible platform whanalysis.com (Angular, Firebase and Python).